



Herndon, VA 20170



507-213-4872



zakyah@proton.me

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

## **Full Stack Web Development**

Career Foundry, Berlin December 2023

Technical Support Fundamentals Coursers, California January 2021

#### **Bachelor of Commerce**

Accounting Osmania University, India March 2010

# WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

- https://github.com/meetZak
- https://meetzak.github.io/portfolio/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/zakaria-abdi-

## **SKILLS**

- Front-End Skills: HTML, CSS & JavaScript
- · Git and Version Control
- Node.js , Rest & API Endpoint
- jQuery, Bootstrap & UI Library
- · Collaboration & Documentation
- Cloud Computing for Web Developers
- · French

## **ZAKARIA ABDI**

#### **SUMMARY**

User-minded Web Developer with a background in mental health. Able to translate skills in teaching and implementing evidence-based practices to effectively communicate with clients and create purposeful web solutions. Driven to grow expertise in website development by utilizing an analytical mindset and creativity to design responsive apps from start to finish.

## WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

## Cloud Computing, September 2023- December 2023

- Deployed a three-tier web application on Amazon Web Services
- Run MongoDB and the API will on EC2 instances.
- Hosted React Client as a static website in an S3 bucket.
- Integrated AWS Software Development Kit (SDK) into API.

## http://zack-lambda-bucket.s3-website-us-east-1.amazonaws.com Client-Side Programming & React, February 2023 - April 2023

- Created a non-relational database (MongoDB) of movements from various styles and to store user data.
- Built a REST-API with Node.js and Express, using Mongoose to interact with the database.
- Tested the API endpoints with Postman, wrote clean and concise documentation, deployed the API with https://render.com/.
- Created two single-page, responsive front-end applications, one using React (following MVC design patter) and the other Angular (with Angular Material). Users can create accounts, browse the library, and save their favorites.

https://zaflix.netlify.app/login

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **ASSISTANT MANAGER**

Albryte Support Services | Sterling, VA | December 2020 - Current

- Leveraged database management system to track and report service hours, details
  of activities and progress on goals.
- Assisted in developing and maintaining user-friendly websites.
- Learn and adopt new technologies quickly and independently.

## **OFFICE COORDINATOR**

HS Bakery | Baltimore, MD | March 2017 - December 2020

- Organized workloads to streamline tasks and efficiently oversee day-to-day operations under tight deadlines.
- Supported internal team members with technical knowledge, operational support, and exemplary customer service.